American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IId. 1837-1844 APS.Archives.IId APS.Archives.IId
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to [A.P.S.], Dec. 1, 1840; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Nagy, Karoly, 1797-1868
    Xerox of A.L.S. 1p.and end. In Hungarian. (from original in Magyar Tudományos Akadémia Konyvtára; 1968)
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 1, 1840; 9x7-1/2; Royal Horticultural Society (Great Britain)
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: George Bentham. 1p.,end.and add.: ford.by Wm. Vaughan. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 2, 1840; 7 3/8" x 9"; Lee, J.
    London, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Forwards copies of last part of Proceedings of the Numismatic Society.
  - Report of committee upon Professor Forshey's paper describing a great mound in Adams County, Mississippi, Dec. 4, 1840; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], D.S.: B[enjamin] W. Richards and G[eorge] M. Wharton. 1p. and end. See APS Proceedings, I, 305-306.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 4, 1840; 7 3/4" x 10"; Darlington, William, 1782-1863
    West Chester, 1p. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of A.P.S. Proceedings, nos. 11, 12, and 13, Wishes to obtain any of the earlier numbers yet available.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 5, 1840; 8" x 10"; Gråberg, Jacob, 1776-1847
    Florence, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Inquires whether nearly fifty of his printed articles and four mss. papers, sent to the A.P.S. between 1815 and 1839, have ever arrived.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 5, 1840; 10x8; Royal Asiatic Society of Great Britain and Ireland
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: R.Clarke. 1p.,end. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 7, 1840; 7 7/8" x 9 13/16"; Forshey, Caleb Goldsmith, 1812-1881
    Natchez, Mississippi, 4 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends set of South Western Journal. Natchez tornado. Mastodon bones.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 7, 1840; 9-3/4x8; Royal Society of Edinburgh
    Edinburgh, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: James D. Forbes. 2p. Thanks for Transactions and lists missing pages in a volume.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., December 8, 1840; 8 3/8" x 10 1/2"; Académie royale des inscriptions et belles lettres (France)
    Paris, 3pp. and endorsement. A.L.S.: Felix Lajard. (In French.) Forwards publications, listed herein, to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 8, 1840; 10x7-1/2; Thomas, R. S.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end.and receipt by James Taylor. Expenses for forwarding society publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 17, 1840; 10-1/2x8; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
    L. 1p. Forwards publications and acknowledges receipt of APS publications.
  - Report of committee on Hare and Boye's paper on perchloric ether, Dec. 18, 1840; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: Henry D. Rogers and Franklin Bache. 1p., end. See APS Proceedings, I, 319-320.
  - Report of committee upon Professor Henry's paper on electro-dynamic induction, Dec. 18, 1840; 9x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], D.S.: R.M. Patterson, A.D. Bache, and Isaiah Lukens. 1p., end. See APS Proceedings, I, 315. Printed: APS Transactions, VI, 303
  - Report of committee on Miss Margaretta H. Morris' communication on the Hessian fly, Dec. 18, 1840; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], D.S.: B[enjamin] H. Coates. 3p. and end. See APS Proceedings, I, 318.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 22, 1840; 6" x 7 3/4"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. News concerning subscriptions to journals and payments therefor.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 28, 1840; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Harris, Thaddeus Mason, 1768-1842
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Regarding various publications of the A.P.S. needed by the Massachusetts Historical Society to complete its collection.
  - Letter to John C. Clark, December 31, 1840; 7 5/8" x 9 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. Receipted bill for printing, $259.83.
  - Resolution., 1840; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Draft of laws reported by the committee to revise the laws of the society [ca.?]. A.D. in hand of Joshua F. Fisher. 1p.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., 1840; 6 1/8" x 8 1/4"; Economical society of Valencia
    Valencia, 1 p. and endorsement. Pr.D.S.: Franco de Sena Chocomeli, Secretary. (In Spanish.)
  - Books possessed by the A.P.S. from Italian societies, [1840]; American Philosophical Society.
  - Concerning membership and officers of the Royal Danish society of sciences at Copenhagan, [ca. 1840]; American Philosophical Society.
  - Report of committee to whom was referred the continuation of [Thomas] Nuttall's paper, Jan. 1, 1841; 9x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Isaac Lea and B. H. Coates. 1p. See APS Proc., II, 3. Printed: APS Trans., VII, 283.
  - Report of committee on rules of order, Jan. 1, 1841; 13x8; American Philosophical Society. Laws and regulations
    [Philadelphia], D.S.: J. K. Kane, R. M. Patterson, and N. Chapman. 2p. and end. See APS [Ms.] Minutes: Jan. 1, 1841, pp.105-106.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 2, 1841; 10x8; Royal Asiatic Society of Great Britain and Ireland
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 4, 1841; 8 1/8" x 10 1/8"; Gråberg, Jacob, 1776-1847
    Librarian of A.P.S., Florence, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding books sent to the A.P.S.
  - Anniversary of the American Philosophical Society, January 6, 1841; 7 1/2" x 12 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. D.S. "The undersigned will dine together on the Birthday of Benjn Franklin 6 Jany 1841." Valuable for autographs. FILM 54-61 FRAME 138
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 7, 1841; 15x9-1/4; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: William J. Hamilton. 1p.,end.and add.: P.Vaughan, Esqr. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 8, 1841; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Rebello, José Silvestre, d. 1844
    Rio, 3 pp. and endorsement. Copy of L. Forwards to the A.P.S.: a complete collection of Registra historica e geografica.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 13, 1841; 8 1/4" x 10 3/8"; Río, Andrés Manuel del, 1764-1849
    Librarian of A.P.S., Mexico, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of A.P.S. Proceedings from March to July, 1840. Sends a specimen of manganate of zinc.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 13, 1841; 10x8; Zoological Society of London
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., January 15, 1841; 8 3/8" x 10 3/4"; Royal society of antiquaries of France
    Paris, 1 p. and endorsement. L.S.: P. Paris. (In French.) Sends to the A.P.S.: Mémoires, XV.
  - Receipt to [David Bailie] Warden, Jan. 16, 1841; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Carilian-Gaeury et Vr. Dalmont
    Paris, D.S.: Leopold. 1p.,end. In French. Publications for the society.
  - Statement to [David Bailie] Warden, Jan. 16, 1841; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Carilian-Gaeury et Vr. Dalmont
    Paris, D.S.: Leopold. 1p.,end. In French. Books purchased for the society.
  - Letter to J[ohn] K. Kane, January 16, 1841; 7 1/2" x 10"; Gråberg, Jacob, 1776-1847
    Florence, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Has sent parcel of his books and pamphlets to A.P.S. Wishes to know if invoices of 1828, 1831, and 1833 arrived safely.
  - Letter to J[ohn] K. Kane, January 20, 1841; 8" x 9 15/16"; Tefft, I. K. (Israel Keech), 1794-1862
    Savannah, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. William B. Stevens appointed to prepare a complete history of Georgia. Requests use to material in possession of A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 20, 1841; 6 3/4" x 8 5/16"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of letter of December 5, 1840. Encloses draft for $76.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 23, 1841; 7x8; Thomas, R. S.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and receipted by James Taylor. Freight on parcel sent to the society.
  - Report of committee on library relative to letter from M. de Candolle, Jan. 26, 1841; 8x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Library
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: G[eorge] Ord, Isaac Hays, and Geo[rge] Campbell. 1p., end. see APS Proceedings, II, 16.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 27, 1841; 7 1/2" x 10"; Gales & Seaton
    Washington, 1 p. and address. L.S. Information regarding the Register of Debates (1824-1837), and other series of public documents.
  - Letter to [John] Waughan [sic], Philadelphia, Jan. 29, 1841; 9-3/4 x8; Bacourt, Adolphe Fourier de, 1801-1865
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French. Presents a new edition of the Dictionary of the French Academy. Refers to Franklin. See APS Proceedings, II, 17. FILM54-67 FRAME 79
  - Psychological observations on the Siamese twins, January, 1841; 8 1/8" x 10 1/2"; Tucker, George, 1775-1861
    Cheng and Eng, made in 1836. University of Virginia, 7 pp. and endorsement. A.Com.S. Printed in Pro., II, 22-28.
  - Report of committee on Isaac Lea's Paper:, Feb. 5, 1841; 9x7; American Philosophical Society
    "Nineteen new species of Colimacea"; Philadelphia, D.S.: Philip H. Nicklin, R. Eglesfeld Griffith, and Isaac Hays. 1p., end. See APS Proc., II, 10-11. Printed: APS Trans., VII, 455ff.
  - Report of committee on William C. Redfield's memoir on the storm, Feb. 5, 1841; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], D.S.: A. D. Bache and S. C. Walker. 1p., end. See APS Proc.,II,10. Printed: APS Trans.,VIII,77
  - Verbal communication by Mr. Du Ponceau about an Indian manuscript which he presented in facsimile, to the Society, Feb. 5, 1841; 4x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D. 1p. Rough note.
  - Letter to P[etty] Vaughan, Feb. 5, 1841; 10x8; Royal College of Surgeons of England
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edm[un]d Balfour, Sec. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for publications. On same sheet is letter from P.Vaughan to [R.Hare?]; Feb. 6, 1841.
  - Letter to [Robert Hare?], Feb. 6, 1841; 10x8; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, A.L.S. 1p. Forwards letter. On same sheet as letter forwarded: Royal college of surgeons of England to P.Vaughan; Feb. 5, 1841.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 10, 1841; 6 3/4" x 8 1/4"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, 2 pp., address and endorsement. L.S. Has received case containing A.P.S. Proceedings, no. 13. Statement of sums advanced, 1840-1841.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 14, 1841; 8" x 10"; Folsom, George, 1802-1869
    New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Winthrop. Acknowledges receipt of volume of Acrelius, loaned to him by the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 15, 1841; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Flourens. 1p.,end.and add. In French. Thanks for Proces-Verbaux.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 17, 1841; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Wood, William B.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Donates a volume of newspapers to the APS, the first English printed copies, done in China.
  - Statement to [David Bailie] Warden, Feb. 17, 1841; 5-1/2x7-1/2; Bossange, Hector, 1795-1884
    Paris, D.S.: Ledoren. 1p. In French. Books for the society.
  - Report of committee on Mr. Walker's paper entitled "Researches on periodic meteors", Feb. 19, 1841; 8x6; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: E. Nulty, R. M. Patterson, and Henry Vethake. 8p., end. See APS Proc.,II, 18ff. Printed: APS Trans., VIII, 87ff.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, Feb. 19, 1841; 10x8; Fisher, Joshua Francis, 1807-1873
    A.L.S. 4p. Concerning arrangement and binding of papers for the A.P.S. Importance cannot be overstressed. Enclosed originally in A.P.S. report; March 5, 1841. See APS Proc., II, 35-36.
  - Letter to [Robert M.] Patterson, February 20, 1841; 8 1/2" x 10 1/2"; Walker, Sears Cook, 1805-1853
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.Com.S. Relating to the formulae developed and used by him in his paper on the periodical meteors of August and November. See Pro., II, 35.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 26, 1841; 6 3/4" x 8 1/4"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Book news. Wishes to subscribe to The National Intelligencer of Gales and Seaton.
  - Letter to [David Bailie] Warden, Paris, March 1, 1841; 9x8; Eyriès, Alexandre
    Havre, L.S. 1p., end.and add. In French. Forwards parcel from John Vaughan.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 1, 1841; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Wood, William B.
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: newspapers published in the English language, at Canton, China. See Pro., II, 29.
  - Report of committee on arrangement and binding of records and documents belonging to the APS, March 5, 1841; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], D.S.: Franklin Bache, J. K. Kane, and A. D. Bache. 3p., end. See also letter from Fisher to A.D.Bache; Feb. 19, 1841, which is part of this report. See APS Proc.,II,35-36.
  - Report of committee on continuation of Isaac Lea's paper on freshwater and land shells, March 5, 1841; 6-1/2x7; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Philip H. Nicklin, R. Eglesfeld Griffith, and Isaac Hays. 1p., end. See APS Proc.,II,30. Printed: APS Trans., 8,163ff.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 6, 1841; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p. and address. L.S. Sends parcel from Royal Society to the A.P.S.
  - Resolution adopted by board of controllers of the public schools, March 9, 1841; 7 13/16" x 10"; First School District of Pennsylvania (Philadelphia, Pa.). Controllers of the Public Schools
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. D.S. Copy. Transit instrument to be deposited for five years in observatory to be erected by the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 9, 1841; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; Schwartz, J. G.
    Librarian of A.P.S., Vienna, 10 pp. and endorsement. A.Com.S. Criticism of [Peter S.] DuPonceau's work on the Chinese language. FILM403 FRAME 150
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 10, 1841; 8" x 10"; Nagy, Károly, 1797-1868
    Vienna, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Lists several donations to the library of the A.P.S. Is directing experiments with the pendulum. See Pro., II, 107.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 10, 1841; 7 3/8" x 9 1/8"; Rebello, José Silvestre, d. 1844
    Rio, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of books and newspapers. Has not received A.P.S. Transactions since 1837; has received only a few numbers of the Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, March 18, 1841; 9-1/2x6; Nagy, Károly, 1797-1868
    Xerox of A.L.S. 2p. In Hungarian. (from original in Magyar Tudományos Akadémia Konyvtára; 1968.)
  - Statement of account to Oscar A. Lawson for drawing fossils, March 19, 1841; 7x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D. 1p.and end.: Receipted by Lawson; April 7, 1841. Approved by Isaac Hays and J.K. Kane.
  - Letter to R[obert] M. Patterson, March 19, 1841; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Nulty, Eugenius
    Philadelphia, 2 pp., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Regrets that he will be unable to attend A.P.S. meeting, and requests Dr. Patterson to "bring forward... one or two motions" on his behalf.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 31, 1841; 7 15/16" x 9"; Wheaton, Henry, 1785-1848
    Librarian of A.P.S., Berlin, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of letter of October 31, 1840, together with books.
  - Report of committee upon measures necessary to secure compliance with regulations on the part of members living within ten miles, April 2, 1841; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: Franklin Bache, J. K. Kane, and A. D. Bache. 3p., end. See APS [Ms.] Minutes: April 2, 1841, p.132.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 2, 1841; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Bonaparte, Charles Lucian, 1803-1857
    Librarian of A.P.S., Rome, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of letter of September, 1840. Concerning meetings of Italian scientific societies.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, philadelphia, April 2, 1841; 11x8-1/4; Akademie der Wissenschaften in Göttingen
    Gottingen, A.L.S.: J.Fr.L.Hausmann. 1p.and add. Is forwarding publication and thanks for proceedings.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 6, 1841; 7 1/8" x 8 7/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Forwards a parcel and savings bank reports. The former will be sent to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 7, 1841; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p. and address. L.S. Sends copies of 24th. Annual Report of Savings Bank to John Vaughan for distribution. Has sent cast of medal of General Washington struck in 1805.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 9, 1841; 8" x 9 7/8"; Engles, William M. (William Morrison), 1797-1867
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Sends minutes [of Presbyterian General Assembly] for 1839 and 1840 to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April 9, 1841; 10x7-3/4; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Josiah Quincy, Pres.and Thadd[eu]s Wm.Harris, Librarian. 1p.,end.and add.: Care of John Vaughan, Esq. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to Peter [S.] DuPonceau, Secretary to the A.P.S., April 16, 1841; 7 3/4" x 12 5/8"; Olcott, James S.
    Alexandria, La., 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Forwards several communications (seemingly missing) to the A.P.S.
  - Report of committee on Simeon Borden's paper on the trigonometrical survey of Massachusetts, April 20, 1841; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Sears C. Walker, R.M. Patterson, 1p. and end. See APS Proc.,II,59. Printed: APS Trans. IX, 33ff.
  - Report of committee on paper by [Elias] Loomis, "Astronomical observations at Hudson Observatory", April 20, 1841; 10-1/2 x 8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Sears C. Walker, R.M. Patterson, and Ge[orge] M. Justice. 1p. and end. See APS Proc.,II, 50. Printed: APS Trans. VIII, 141.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April 20, 1841; 11x8-1/4; Akademie der Wissenschaften in Göttingen
    Gottingen, A.L.S.: J.Fr.L.Hausmann. 1p.and add., end. Thanks for Transactions and notifies the APS of publication en route.
  - Receipt to John Vaughan for payment for ice, April 24-Oct. 28, 1841; 3x6-1/2; Mills & Lewis
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 26, 1841; 7 1/4" x 9 15/16"; Silliman, Benjamin, 1816-1885
    Yale Coll[ege], New Haven, 2 pp. A.L.S. Sends engraved head of his father, together with "a short notice of his history" by Professor Kingsley. Franklin letter at Hartford. FILM54-61 FRAME139
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 26, 1841; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Tefft, I. K. (Israel Keech), 1794-1862
    Savannah, 4 pp. and address. A.L.S. Thanks A.P.S. for volumes presented to the Georgia Historical Society. Progress of William B. Stevens on the History of Georgia.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 28, 1841; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Hassler, F. R. (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
    Washington city, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Relative to an article on the barometer for the Society's Transactions.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, April, 1841; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Magyar Tudományos Akadémia. Könyvtár
    Xerox of L. 1p. In French. (from original in Magyar Tudományos Akadémia Konyvtára.) Acknowledgment of receipt of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 1, 1841; 11x8-1/2; Kongelige Danske videnskabernes selskab
    Philadelphia; Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: A.Oersted. 1p.,end. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., May 3, 1841; 8 1/2" x 10 3/4"; Royal society of sciences of Copenhagen.
    [Copenhagen], 1 p. and endorsements. D.S.: H. Orsted. Presents to the A.P.S.: Memoirs, VIII, and other listed items.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, May 6, 1841; 10x7-3/4; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Josiah Quincy, Pres.and Thadd[eu]s Wm.Harris, Librarian. 1p.,end.and add.: Care of J. Vaughan, Esq. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 7, 1841; 10x8; Cuthbert, John A. (John Albert), 1788-1881
    Hamburg, A.L.S. 1p.,receipted by J.A. Latimer, add.,and end. Freight on forwarding society publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 7, 1841; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Glad to hear that John is recovering. Encloses list of books in box for the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 10, 1841; 5" x 8"; Short, Charles Wilkins, 1794-1863
    Louisville, 1 p. and address. L. Unsigned. Copy. Extract only. Donates "large collection of Western and Southern plants" to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 11, 1841; 7 15/16" x 10"; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Washington, 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Orders A.P.S. Transactions, n.s., III and IV. With regard to Mr. Hassler's paper on the barometer.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 12, 1841; 9-1/2x8; Royal Geographical Society (Great Britain)
    Printed L.filled in in Ms.S.: Jul[ia]n R. Jackson. 1p.,end. Thanks for the Transactions and Proceedings.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 13, 1841; 10-1/2x8; Bossange, Edouard
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and add., end. Will be happy to continue forwarding society publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 15, 1841; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Atlee, Washington L. (Washington Lemuel), 1808-1878
    Lancaster, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Forwards original ms. of his review of Professor [James P.] Espy's theory of storms, for consideration by the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 17, 1841; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843
    ----, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Name of gentleman "who offered...to effect an exchange of fossils" was Professor Toggetti of Florence.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, May 18, 1841; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Académie royale des sciences, des lettres et des beaux-arts de Belgique
    Brussels, L.S.: Quetelet. 1p.and add.: Forwarded by Wm.Vaughan. In French. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, May 19, 1841; 7 5/8" x 9 13/16"; Gilpin, Joshua
    President of A.P.S., Kentmere, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents a piece of stone taken from the summit of Monnt Blanc, and six inches of the tusk of a sword fish.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 19, 1841; 7 15/16" x 10"; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Librarian of A.P.S., Washington, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Mr. Hassler's paper on the barometer, together with drawings, will soon be ready. Requests A.P.S. Transactions, n.s., III and IV.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 19, 1841; 10x8; Zoological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wm.Ogilby. 1p.,end. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, May 20, 1841; 15x9-1/2; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: William J. Hamilton. 1p.end.and add.: P.Vaughan... Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Report of committee to which was referred the letter from the president of the Royal Society of Sciences, Agriculture and Arts of Lille, May 21, 1841; 12x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: Peter S. DuPonceau and R. M. Patterson. 1p. and end. See APS Proceedings, II, 69-70.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 21, 1841; 12-3/4x8; Royal Numismatic Society (Great Britain)